

Md. Mahmudul Islam

### **CONTACT**

Address: 1005 West-Shewrapara, Mirpur, Dhaka.

Permanent Address: Banshopata, Talora, Dupchanchia, Bogura

Phone: +8801521404361

Email: mahmudul7959@gmail.com

### **PROFILE**

#### Portfolio:

https://mahmud.prottov.com.bd/

#### LinkedIn:

https://www.lipkedip.com/ip/mahmudul7959/

#### Github:

https://github.com/Mahmud-CSE16

#### StopStalk:

https://www.stopstalk.com/user/profile/Mah mud\_CSF16



# **Summary**

I'm fully passionate to develop something new with the latest technology. I'm well-versed in numerous programming languages. I have experience developing 10+ mobile apps and 3+ websites as well as working as team member and lead the team.



# **Skill highlights**



#### Flutter (Android, iOS and Web)

- Bloc Pattern & MVVM
- Customize all kind of widgets as required
- · Rest APIs handling



#### Django

- Database (MySQL and Postgres)
- · GUI for machine learning
- Rest APIs
- Auto generated firebase push notification



#### **AWS - Cloud Services**

- · Global cloud platform
- · Cloud storage platform
- EC2, S3, Database

#### **Extra Skills**













**Firebase** 

Map

Git

Android

Xd

React





ML



# **Education**

#### **BSc**

- CSE (Final year)
- CGPA: 3.13
- KUET

#### HSC

- Science
- GPA: 5.0 (All)
- Police lines School and collage, Bogura.

#### SSC

- Science
- GPA: 5.0 (All)
- Talora Altaf Ali High School.



# **Experiences**



### Prottoy visual learning platform Chief Technical Officer

Aug-2020 - Present

- To lead the technical team for developing android and web application
- To develop a visual learning app
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=bd.com.prottoy



### Ongrocery

#### **Software Engineer**

May-2021 - Present

- Ongrocery is a shopping app to sell grocery products from around the world
- My work is to develop and improve features in Ongrocery App
- Android https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.zatiq.expresscart
- iOS https://apps.apple.com/app/id1522292588



### EasyTrax Ltd

#### Flutter App Development (contract)

May-2020 - May-2021

- Developing complex UI/UX for Easytrax GPS Tracking App.
- Cooperate with designer, developers and Chief Operating Officer at Easytrax Ltd.
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bd.pro.easytraxstandard

UI Design – Adobe XD to HTML, CSS, Javascript (contract)

Sep-2019 - April-2020

- Developed numerous email templates for emailing to clients with a clean interface.
- Developed some UI for Easytrax and Easyhat website.
- https://crm.easytrax.com.bd/crm/registration



**Simplex** (Career Development Associate)

### **Android Development** (contract)

May-2019 – Feb-2020

- Developed some exam preparatory apps for Project Management courses.
- · Worked with senior person who has a vast knowledge of Project Management & Planning
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.simplex.mahmud.cbapsimplified



# **Extra-Curricular Activities**



**Bit2Bite** (Software Research & Development community of KUET)

#### **Vice President**

Sep-2020 - Present

- Through **Bit2Bite** we organize workshops on software research and development where our seniors are training us(junior).
- I conducted 3 workshops as a trainer.



HACK (Hardware Acceleration Club of KUET)

### **Organizing Secretary**

March-2020 - Present

- Through HACK we organize workshops on Hardware and IOT where our seniors are training us(junior).
- I conducted 5 workshops as a trainer.



## References

#### Fahim Al Mahmud Ashik

Co-Founder and CTO at Zatiq
Co-Founder and CTO at Expresscart.

- +8801711394908
- ashikcse12@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashikcse12/

#### Abul Bashar Md. Sharif

**Director at Easytrax Ltd.** 

- +8801711-506350
- bashar@easytrax.com.bd
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/abmsharif/